[{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"1. An admiral of this kingdom was said to have tightened iron ropes between enemy fleet groups during a battle that he had prepared his soldiers for by saying that “those who seek death shall live; those who seek life shall die.” The “forest of scholars” faction revered a group of officials who plotted to assassinate the ruler of this kingdom known as the “six martyred ministers.” As he died, a military leader of this kingdom instructed, “Beat my war drums. Do not announce my death.” A royal research institute called the Hall of Worthies was set up by a ruler of this kingdom who ensured commoners’ education by creating a new alphabet. “Turtle ships” were created by Yi Sun-shin, an admiral of, for 10 points, what kingdom ruled by Sejong the Great, the creator of hangul? ","answer":"ANSWER: Joseon (“JO-sun”) Dynasty [or Choson Dynasty; or Kingdom of Joseon or Chosun; prompt on Korea or Hanguk] <World History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"2. A group of oligomers of these molecules produced by enzymatic degradation are historically named after Franz Schardinger. A group of oligomers of these molecules are produced using the enzyme CGTase (“C-G-T-ace”). Cyclic oligomers of these molecules form a common stationary phase in chiral chromatography. These molecules undergo mutarotation to interconvert between anomers. The stereochemistry of these molecules is described by a diagram consisting of a vertical line intersecting several horizontal lines. These molecules are classified as alpha or beta based on whether a hydroxyl points up or down on a Haworth projection. Polymers of these monomers include cellulose and glycogen. For 10 points, identify these molecules, which include glucose. ","answer":"ANSWER: monosaccharides [or sugars; or oligosaccharides; or carbohydrates; or hexoses; or pentoses; or aldoses; or ketoses; or dextrins; or cyclodextrins] <Chemistry> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"3. An 1848 issue of The Athenaeum accused one philosopher of plagiarizing an argument mentioning one of these figures from the Dutch philosopher Bernard Nieuwentyt (“NEE-wen-tight”). A book named for one of these figures features a thought experiment in which a computer program attempts to type the phrase “Methinks it is like a weasel” to demonstrate non-random cumulative selection. An 1802 book that compares the human eye to a telescope begins by comparing the discoveries of a stone and an object created by one of these people. A book by Richard Dawkins titled for a “blind” one of these people criticizes an analogy mentioning one of them presented in William Paley’s Natural Theology. Deists often make use of an analogy comparing God to, for 10 points, what type of craftsman who creates timepieces? ","answer":"ANSWER: watchmaker [accept clockmaker; accept The Blind Watchmaker; accept a person who makes watches or clocks; prompt on craftsman until read; prompt on God, a deity, a Creator, a demiurge by asking “that is compared to what type of person?”] <Philosophy> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"4. Susan Stryker addressed a character in this novel in an essay on “performing transgender rage.” An old orange seller gives this book to a prince at the end of a fable in Oranges Are Not the Only Fruit by Jeannette Winterson, whose 2019 novel reimagines its author as a transgender doctor. At the end of this novel, a character vows to build himself a “funeral pile,” then is “borne away by the waves and lost in darkness and distance.” A man describes his mission to discover “the wondrous power which attracts the needle” to his sister Margaret Saville in the first letter of this epistolary novel. After a failed experiment in the Orkneys, the title character of this novel pursues the creature who murdered his fiancée Elizabeth into the Arctic. For 10 points, name this novel subtitled “The Modern Prometheus” by Mary Shelley. ","answer":"ANSWER: Frankenstein <British Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"5. A nationalist from this region inspired the far-right meme “Europe of 100 Flags.” A Basque folktale about a witch who threatens a cute cow inspired the Nazi-sympathizing “Seven Brothers” Arts and Crafts movement in this region, where people go on “pardon” pilgrimages and do “an dro” circle dances at fest-noz gatherings. As in Norfolk, heraldic ermine spots inspired the black-and-white Kroaz Du (“kr’wahz due”) flag of this region, famed for its savory buckwheat galette, the kaletez. The ancient seafaring Veneti name this region’s city of Vannes (“vahn”). Words for “cake” and “butter” name the pastry kouign-amann (“QUEEN-yah-mahn”) in this region’s Celtic language. The medieval duchy in this region was led from Rennes (“ren”) and Nantes (“nahnt”). For 10 points, name this peninsular region of northwest France west of Normandy. ","answer":"ANSWER: Brittany [or Bretagne; accept Bretoned or Breizhiz; prompt on Armorica; accept the départements Côtes-d’Armor or Finistère or Ille-et-Vilaine or Morbihan; prompt on France or French Republic or République française] (The first sentence refers to Yann Fouéré. The second sentence is about the Seiz Breur; the reason they liked the folktale was that, of the seven brothers who become cows, the Breton cow is loved best by their sister.) <Geography> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"6. A style of musical notation from this country uses an X to denote the first beat of a rhythmic or metrical phrase and a zero to denote an “empty beat.” A musician from this country collaborated with flutist Bud Shank on the 1962 album Improvisations. A musical system from this country that is similar to solfège (“SOUL-fezh”) uses the note names S, R, G, M, P, D, and N. A musician from this country who collaborated with Yehudi Menuhin (“yeh-HOO-dee MEN-yoo-in”) on the album East Meets West gave George Harrison lessons in an instrument popular in it for a part in the Beatles song “Norwegian Wood.” Mode and meter are roughly analogous to this country’s traditional rāga and tāḷa musical systems, which are used in carnatic music. For 10 points, name this home country of the sitar player Ravi Shankar. ","answer":"ANSWER: India [or Bhārat] <Classical Music> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"1. While they are not dogs, these animals are hosts for every lyssavirus except for the Mossola virus. These animals are the vector of the MERS and SARS coronaviruses, as well as Henipaviruses. These animals are believed to be the natural reservoir for Marburg virus and ebolavirus. These animals are being killed by the fungus Pseudogymnoascus destructans, which causes white nose syndrome. For 10 points, name these flying mammals that often spread disease through guano. ","answer":"ANSWER: bats [or Chiropterans; accept specific types of bats like the fruit bat; accept flying foxes] <Biology> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"8. A poem in this collection describes “a fish infinitely fastened to my soul” and “fortunate isles that are white and sweet.” An “abstracted pale mourner, standing that way against the old propellers of twilight” appears in another poem from this collection that describes a “magnificent and fecund and magnetic slave.” That poem in this collection opens with the line “The light wraps you in its mortal flame.” This collection contains a poem that notes how “the night is starry and the stars are blue and shiver in the distance,” as well as the poem “Drunk With Pines.” The assertion that “love is so short, forgetting is so long” appears in a poem from this collection that opens, “Tonight I can write the saddest lines.” For 10 points, name this collection of romantic poems by Pablo Neruda. ","answer":"ANSWER: Twenty Love Poems and a Song of Despair [or Veinte poemas de amor y una canción desesperada] <World/Other Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"9. A Wakuénai (“wa-KWEH-nai”) trickster-creator god who is “made from” these objects finds Anaconda-Person’s penis. The Hupda “Son of” these objects defeats the first Juruparí. In the Bororo “Bird-Nester’s Aria,” spirit fish leave these objects from the hero’s father on a lake bottom. The “head variants” of the Maya numerals 13 through 19 represent the value of 10 with one of these objects from God A. In the Popol Vuh (“vookh”), Xibalba’s (“shee-ball-ba’s”) staff bearers are named for these objects, which they can turn people into. Cihuacōātl (“see-wah-ko-ah-tull”) grinds these inedible objects to flour for dough in Tamoanchan. A quail gnaws at these objects after Xolotl (“sho-LOH-tull”) helps steal them from Mictlān (“meekt-LAHN”). Quetzalcoatl creates the fifth world’s people by adding his blood to these body parts. For 10 points, Mexicans sculpt sugar into what body parts on Day of the Dead? ","answer":"ANSWER: bones [accept skeletons; accept specific bones such as skulls or jaws or mandibles; or baak or omitl or omitetl; accept Chamiabac or Bone Staff or Chamiaholom or Skull Staff; prompt on connective tissue or body parts or organs; accept Ku Teh or “Son of the Bone”] <Mythology> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"0. One ruler of this empire may have adopted the pseudonym of a black-robed monk to criticize the Greek alphabet. A rock relief carved in this empire depicts a life-size rider 75 feet up a sheer cliff in the Madara Plateau. During the reign of Leo the Isaurian, this empire’s ruler Tervel rescued Constantinople from its second Arab siege. After swaying the population by building a church for Saint Demetrius, the brothers Asen and Peter led an uprising that restored this empire. Saints Clement and Naum taught in this empire’s literary schools at Ohrid and Preslav, where the Cyrillic script was developed. After the Battle of Kleidion, prisoners from this empire were separated into groups of one-hundred and blinded by the Byzantines. For 10 points, name this Slavic empire whose warriors were “slain” by Basil II. ","answer":"ANSWER: Bulgarian Empire [or First Bulgarian Empire; or Second Bulgarian Empire; or Bulgar Khanate; or Danube Bulgaria] (The first sentence refers to the theory that the author of On the Letters was Tsar Simeon I.) <European History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"4. Another group of these objects has members separated by regions named for Johann Encke and James Keeler. These objects tend to form [emphasize] within the Roche (“rohsh”) limit of a larger object. The gravitational forces exerted by “shepherd moons” enable these objects to keep their integrity. The “A” and “B” members of one of these objects are separated by the Cassini Division. For 10 points, name these systems of dust and other solid matter often found orbiting planets such as Saturn. ","answer":"ANSWER: planetary rings [or ring systems; accept any specific named examples such as rings of Saturn] <Other Science (Astronomy)> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"2. The 18th-century theater director John Rich popularized this art form in England after being inspired by innovations made by the Italian Players, who were exiled to the Left Bank by Louis XIV. A Swiss collective uses elaborate, rearrangeable masks made of clay and toilet paper in performances of this type. Étienne Decroux (“ay-tee-EN duh-CROO”) spent decades perfecting the postmodern “corporeal” type of this art form. Jean-Louis Barrault (“bah-RO”) performed this art form in the film Children of Paradise. A famous performer of this art form created a piece satirizing the four ages of man in the guise of Bip the Clown, and referred to this art form as “the art of silence.” For 10 points, Marcel Marceau practiced what performing art that stereotypically involves pretending to be in a box? ","answer":"ANSWER: mime performance [or mime arts word forms like miming; or corporeal mime; or pantomime; accept dumbshows; or mumming or mummery; prompt on clowning until “Bip” is read] (Louis XIV banned the Italian Players from speaking in performances after insulting his mistress, resulting in the birth of French pantomime; the second sentence refers to Mummenschanz.) <Other Arts (Performing)> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"3. This concept titles Reginald Ray’s book highlighting Kadam and Rimé (“ree-MAY”) spiritualism in Tibetan Buddhism. The last four lines of the long Mūl Mantar each end with the Punjabi word for this concept, which also appears after the opening Ik Onkar (“ick OWN-car”) declaring God’s oneness as one of His names. The saṁvṛiti or “conventional” level of this concept is distinct from its “empty” or “ultimate” form in a doctrine formulated by the Madhyamaka founder Nāgārjuna. It’s not existence, but this concept, consciousness, and bliss describe Brahman in the word Sacchidānanda. The Turning the Wheel of Dharma Sūtra outlines nirodha and samudaya as part of a set of these concepts describing how a magga path can end dukkha, or suffering. For 10 points, name this concept exemplified by the Buddha’s “four noble” ones. ","answer":"ANSWER: truths [or word forms like true; accept righteousness or being real or actual or good; accept Four Noble Truths or catvāri āryasatyāni; accept satya or satnaam or Sach Khand; do not accept or prompt on “dharma” or “dhamma”] (The first sentence is from Indestructible Truth: The Living Spirituality of Tibetan Buddhism.) <Religion> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"4. This character walks several times from an inn to the box office of a theater and back while getting very confused about the right way to buy tickets to see a tenor named Lagardy. After this character finds a misplaced green silk cigar case, he tries smoking after dinner to show off, but instead gets ill. In the opening chapter of the novel, this character is forced to write “I am ridiculous” twenty times in Latin after losing his cap on the first day at school. When this character botches a surgical operation on a stable groom’s clubfoot, his reputation in Yonville (“yon-VEEL”) declines. He dies of grief after love letters reveal that his deceased wife had affairs with Rodolphe Boulanger and Léon Dupuis. For 10 points, name this husband of Emma in the most famous novel of Gustave Flaubert. ","answer":"ANSWER: Charles Bovary [or Charles Bovary; or Monsieur Bovary; prompt on Bovary] <European Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"5. One ethnography relates how a form of this practice called suvasova is thought to cause maggots to grow in the body. Arthur Wolf tested a hypothesis concerning this practice by observing a different practice’s bint ‘amm and sim pua types in Morocco and Taiwan. When Margaret Mead asked an Arapesh man about this practice, he responded “with whom will you hunt?” if this were to occur. Marriage rates of Israeli children raised in the same kibbutz (“kee-BOOTS”) were used to explain the existence of restrictions on this behavior in the Westermarck effect. According to the alliance theory of Lévi-Strauss, prohibitions on this practice create social bonds by promoting exogamy. For 10 points, a universal taboo exists concerning what practice of having sex with close kin? ","answer":"ANSWER: incest [or incest taboo; accept having sex with family or blood relatives or more specific answers like having sex with a sibling, brother, sister, father, mother, or cousin; accept inbreeding; accept marrying a relative or family member or equivalents; prompt on sex, mating, or marriage; prompt on endogamy] <Social Science (Anthropology)> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"6. In this country, the engineer Enrico Dalgas founded a “Heath Society” whose reclamation efforts allowed many cooperative dairy and pig farms to spring up in previously-barren lands. The concept of “folk high schools” for adult education was pioneered by a pastor who influenced this country’s nationalism during its “Golden Age” in the first half of the 19th century. A windmill at Dybbøl (“DUE-bull”) became a symbol of this country due to a conflict that Lord Palmerston said was only understood by an insane German professor, Prince Albert, and himself. Because of this country’s part in the Continental System, its capital was bombarded by the British navy during the Napoleonic Wars. For 10 points, what Scandinavian country fought Prussia in two wars over the duchies of Schleswig and Holstein? ","answer":"ANSWER: Denmark (The unnamed pastor is N. F. S. Grundtvig.) <European History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"7. For complex potentials, the orthogonal Wannier functions can be used as a basis set for these particles’ wavefunctions. In one model, these particles are assumed to instantly thermalize after collisions, and their self-interactions are entirely neglected. That model can be improved upon by adding a weak perturbing potential. At low temperatures, these particles contribute a linear term to the heat capacity of a metal. Arnold Sommerfeld created a theory in which these particles move freely by adding quantum statistics to the earlier Drude model. The number of these particles is increased by n-type doping semiconductors. The absence of one of these particles in a conduction band is known as a hole. For 10 points, the primary charge carrier in a metal is what particle with a negative charge? ","answer":"ANSWER: electrons <Physics> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"8. For 10 points, name this president whose popularity tanked because of the Panic of 1837, leading him to lose his re-election bid to William Henry Harrison. ","answer":"ANSWER: Martin Van Buren <American History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"9. This character reveals an interest in science after he tries to return a “bio-chemistry” book that the narrator had left in a carriage. This character worries about the suffering of a twittering “little animal,” which he discovers is actually a woman’s hair, before passing out. A novel ends with a woman remarking that there isn’t much difference between this character’s relatives “up at the farm” and “down in the graveyard.” The driver Harmon Gow describes this “ruin of a man” in the novel’s frame story. This man lies about having to pick up cash from Andrew Hale to excuse himself from driving his sickly wife to the Flats. This man’s wife Zeena takes care of him and his cousin Mattie Silver after they attempt suicide by sled crash. For 10 points, name this title character of a novella by Edith Wharton. ","answer":"ANSWER: Ethan Frome [accept either name] <American Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"0. A green one of these objects features in a quintessential Art Deco self-portrait by the Polish baroness Tamara de Łempicka (“wem-PEETS-ka”). A gray, wave-like shape and three green hills appear in the last panel of an “Abstract” triptych focused on one of these objects by Giacomo Balla. In a Roy Lichtenstein painting titled for one of these things, a man with blue-tinged hair looks sidelong at a woman in a bright yellow leopard-print jacket. In a text set during a night in Venice, one of these objects is compared to a shark as it is surrounded by a crowd of fishermen. One of these objects that “seems to run on machine-gun fire” is said to be “more beautiful than the Victory of Samothrace” in Filippo Marinetti’s Futurist Manifesto. For 10 points, René Lalique’s Victoire is a hood ornament for what sort of vehicle? ","answer":"ANSWER: cars [or motorcars; or automobiles; accept In the Car or Driving; accept more specific types like Bugattis; prompt on vehicles] <Painting/Sculpture> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"1. The title character of one this author’s stories is found strangled near his mother’s grave, next to a poem that he wrote in blood. A soldier shoots his father and his horse off a cliff in another story by this author. A work by this author of “The Death of Halpin Frayser” says that education “disguises from the foolish their lack of understanding” and that a cynic’s “faulty vision sees things as they are, and not as they ought to be.” In a story by this author of “A Horseman in the Sky,” a disguised Federal scout tricks the protagonist into trying to use driftwood to sabotage a railroad. In that story by him, hallucinations of escaping flit through Peyton Farquhar’s mind as he is hanged. For 10 points, name this American author of “An Occurrence at Owl Creek Bridge” and The Devil’s Dictionary. ","answer":"ANSWER: Ambrose Bierce <American Literature> Bonuses "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this prolific jazz pianist and rival of James P. Johnson, who composed widely-covered standards like “Squeeze Me” and “(What Did I Do to Be So) Black and Blue” with lyricist Andy Razaf (“RAZZ-uff”). ","answer":"ANSWER: Fats Waller [or Thomas Wright “Fats” Waller] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] Fats Waller and James P. Johnson pioneered this style of jazz piano while working in Harlem. This style is named for the leaping motion made by the left hand, which plays alternating root notes and chords in an “oom-pah” rhythm. ","answer":"ANSWER: Harlem stride piano [or stride style] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] Another musician nicknamed “Fats” composed early rock ’n’ roll hits like “Blueberry Hill” and had this surname. Eric Clapton played guitar on “Layla,” a song by a band named for Derek and some of these objects. ","answer":"ANSWER: Dominos [accept Fats Domino; accept Derek & and the Dominos] <Other Arts (Jazz)> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this practice collected in Beautiful Beyond, produced by Smithsonian Folkways. In The Jesus Road, Luke E. Lassiter examined the prominent role of this practice among Kiowa (“KYE-oh-wuh”) Christians, who often join choirs. ","answer":"ANSWER: singing [or songs; or singing hymns; accept chanting; prompt on music] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] A Hopi song about the Crow Mother recounts the Bean Dance during the katsina season, which begins with this event. A tradition that celebrates this event with Alban Arthan places it opposite Litha on an eight-pointed wheel. ","answer":"ANSWER: winter solstice [accept Yule; prompt on partial answer; or hiemal solstice; or hibernal solstice; accept midwinter; accept Soyal or Shakalo; prompt on Sabbaths] (The wheel is the Pagan “Wheel of the Year.”) "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] At each festival after the winter solstice, katsinas wear horned masks as part of different stages of this kind of ritual, also used in a form of Pueblo prayer. Oberammergau, Esparreguera, Iztapalapa, and Tyrol use this kind of ritual to depict the Passion on Easter. ","answer":"ANSWER: prayer dramas [accept passion plays or the Easter pageant; or theatre; or performances; or spectacles; or shows; prompt on dance by asking “dance as part of what kind of performance?”] <Religion> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this 1939 novel whose title is derived from an Emily Dickinson poem. This novel centers on the depressed Sasha Jansen’s return to Paris. ","answer":"ANSWER: Good Morning, Midnight "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"6. This novel is told from the perspective of the Creole heiress Antoinette Cosway. ","answer":"ANSWER: Wide Sargasso Sea "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] Wide Sargasso Sea was penned as an “anti-colonial” response to this Charlotte Brontë novel. Cosway’s roles as the “madwoman in the attic” and as Mr. Rochester’s wife are both directly lifted from this novel. ","answer":"ANSWER: Jane Eyre: An Autobiography <World/Other Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this property. Informally, it means that you don’t have to lift your pencil off the page when sketching a function. ","answer":"ANSWER: continuity [or continuous] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] In one statement of the continuous mapping theorem, mappings from X to Y are continuous if and only if any subset of Y with this property maps from a subset of X with this property. A ball with this property does not contain its corresponding sphere. ","answer":"ANSWER: openness "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] The smallest [emphasize] closed set containing a given subset of a metric space is known as the closure; if the closure is simply the space itself, then the subset is said to have this property in the metric space. ","answer":"ANSWER: dense <Other Science (Math)> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this reformer, nicknamed “Orator” by Robert Southey, who was the main speaker at the Spa Fields meetings. In another incident, soldiers attempted to arrest this man after he was invited to speak by the Patriotic Union Society. ","answer":"ANSWER: Henry Hunt "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] Henry Hunt was the main speaker at the demonstration that was attacked by cavalry troops in this massacre. This 1819 massacre occurred in Manchester was given a name paralleling Napoleon’s final loss. ","answer":"ANSWER: Peterloo Massacre "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] In the aftermath of the massacre, Hunt was convicted of sedition and Lord Sidmouth passed the repressive Six Acts, inspiring Arthur Thistlewood to plan this conspiracy to kill Sidmouth and his cabinet. ","answer":"ANSWER: Cato Street Conspiracy <European History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name these objects. After declaring that “my spirit is too weak,” the speaker compares himself to a “sick eagle looking at the sky” as he sees these objects in that John Keats sonnet. ","answer":"ANSWER: the Elgin Marbles [or the Parthenon Marbles; accept “On Seeing the Elgin Marbles”; prompt on marble statues, Greek statues, or similar answers] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] This poet alluded to Richard Payne Knight’s zany opinion that the Elgin Marbles weren’t of Greek origin in a passage beginning “The critics say that epics have died out” in the epic poem Aurora Leigh. ","answer":"ANSWER: Elizabeth Barrett Browning [or Elizabeth Barrett; prompt on Browning] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] In another Keats sonnet about experiencing a piece of Greek culture, he wrote of feeling like a “watcher of the skies” upon “first looking into” George Chapman’s translation of this blind poet’s work. ","answer":"ANSWER: Homer <British Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this class of monster similar to the hopping Chinese Jiāngshī (“jyahng-shur”), glowing Ashanti Obayifo, and proboscis-tongued Filipino Aswang. These bloodsucking beings were popularized by Gothic novels like Carmilla and Dracula. ","answer":"ANSWER: vampires [or vampiri; accept nosferatu; accept moroi; accept xīxuèguǐ; accept, but DO NOT REVEAL, any of the answers in the second part below] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] Greeks, Albanians, Romanians, and Slavs all warn of these screeching vampires that turn into insects or owls. Polyphonte became one of these hags, which are linguistic cognates of the Italian word for “witch,” which itself names an Italian literary prize and a Tomie dePaola tale about a spaghetti witch grandmother. ","answer":"ANSWER: strīx [or striges; or strigoi; or shtriga; or strega or streghe or Strega Nona or strzyga or stryha; accept Strega Prize or Premio Strega; accept Strigidae or Striginae, a family of owls named for them] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] The Sumerian proto-vampire edimmu can be dispelled by performing this action, which was done with a “portal” at the Poulnabrone (“pohl-nuh-brohn”) site. After being caught at this action, a woman cries, “See what I suffer, and at whose hands, because I revered reverence!” ","answer":"ANSWER: conducting a proper burial [or burial rites; accept burying Polynices; accept portal tombs; accept graves or sepulchers or crypts or catacombs; prompt on cairns or dolmens by asking “what practice did those stone structures usually mark the site of?”] (The quote is from Antigone.) <Mythology> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this event that overthrew colonial rule of Saint Domingue under the leadership of Toussaint Louverture. ","answer":"ANSWER: Haitian Revolution [or word forms] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] In this 1938 book, C. L. R. James argues that Louverture represented the apotheosis of revolutionary ideals that were only partially realized in France itself. ","answer":"ANSWER: The Black Jacobins [or The Black Jacobins: Toussaint L’Ouverture and the San Domingo Revolution] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] James cast this friend and actor as the title character in his play Toussaint Louverture. Jackie Robinson testified against this blacklisted performer before HUAC (“HYOO-ack”) because this man had declared African-Americans would support the USSR in the Cold War. ","answer":"ANSWER: Paul Robeson <World History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name these two artists who collaborated on Little Girl in a Blue Armchair. One of them painted the other examining herself in a mirror in At the Milliner’s, and also made several paintings of her at the Louvre. ","answer":"ANSWER: Mary Cassatt AND Edgar Degas "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] Despite disliking its name, both Degas and Cassatt are considered prominent members of this art movement, whose name derives from a Claude Monet painting. ","answer":"ANSWER: impressionism [or word forms] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] This museum held an exhibition in 2014 dedicated to the relationship between Degas and Cassatt. This museum, also home to Watson and the Shark and The Voyage of Life, contains an East building with an H-shaped façade designed by I. M. Pei. ","answer":"ANSWER: National Gallery of Art [or NGA] <Painting/Sculpture> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this process of electron emission following the filling of an inner-shell vacancy. It is dominant at low atomic numbers over internal conversion. ","answer":"ANSWER: Auger (“oh-ZHAY”) effect "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"1. ","answer":"ANSWER: alpha particles "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] Because of their high energy, alpha particles have an extremely high relative biological effectiveness, or RBE. The RBE of a given radiation type is defined as the ratio between two values of this quantity measured in grays. ","answer":"ANSWER: absorbed dose [prompt on dose; do not accept or prompt on “effective dose” or “equivalent dose”] <Physics> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this man, whose confession to Danforth is nullified when he refuses to hand over a signed contract, and tears it up instead. That confession is interrupted by the entrance of Rebecca Nurse, whom this man refuses to indict. ","answer":"ANSWER: John Proctor [accept either name] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] Proctor justifies those actions to Danforth saying “Because it is [this thing],” as he wonders “How may I live without [this thing]?” He then continues his plea, saying “I have given you my soul, leave me [this thing]!” ","answer":"ANSWER: his name [or “my name”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] John Proctor leaves to be hanged at the end of this Arthur Miller play about the Salem witch trials. ","answer":"ANSWER: The Crucible <American Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] Give this Greek-language term used in the Symposium by Diotima to describe Eros, a daemon accessible from both the human and divine realms. ","answer":"ANSWER: metaxy [or metaxu] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] Simone Weil used the Platonic cave and the Christian cross as metaphors for this concept, which she believed was a constant reminder of the distance to God. John McTaggart’s A and B series are two ways of interpreting this concept. ","answer":"ANSWER: time [accept temporal ordering of events; accept the unreality of time; accept tense] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] Simon Leys translated an NYRB Classics edition of a book by Weil on the abolition of these entities. James Madison and Alexander Hamilton warned about the dangers of these organizations in Federalists Papers 9 and 10, referring to them as “factions.” ","answer":"ANSWER: political parties [or political party; accept On the Abolition of All Political Parties] <Philosophy> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this politician who chaired a Senate hearing on comic books and sponsored an expansion of the Clayton Antitrust Act with Emmanuel Celler. ","answer":"ANSWER: Estes Kefauver (“ESS-tiss KEE-faw-ver”) [or Carey Estes Kefauver] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] Kefauver won re-election to a third Senate term despite his refusal to sign this document, which accused the Supreme Court of a “clear abuse of judicial power” after Brown v. Board. ","answer":"ANSWER: Southern Manifesto [or the Declaration of Constitutional Principles] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] Kefauver chaired a namesake committee investigating this nebulous criminal organization, which included Frank Costello and Meyer Lansky. Thomas Dewey rose to fame prosecuting this organization’s enforcers in Murder, Inc. ","answer":"ANSWER: The American Mafia [or the Italian Mafia; or the Cosa Nostra; or the Jewish Mob; or the National Crime Syndicate] <American History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name these chemical species that bind to a metal center to form a coordination complex. ","answer":"ANSWER: ligands (“LIG-unds”) "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] The adjective non-innocent refers to ligands for which this quantity is unclear, such as in the nitrosyl ligand. Free energy is plotted against this quantity in a Frost diagram. ","answer":"ANSWER: oxidation state [or oxidation number] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] Since oxidation state for ligands is often poorly defined, ligands are classified using the covalent bond classification method instead. This letter is used to indicate ligands that donate one electron and accept one electron from a metal center through a two-electron covalent bond. ","answer":"ANSWER: X [or X-type ligands] <Chemistry> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this composer of Kamarinskaya who, in 1884, founded a namesake annual prize whose early winners included Cesar Cui (“say-ZAR KYOO-ee”) and Anatoly Lyadov. ","answer":"ANSWER: Mikhail Glinka "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] This composer was also an early winner of the Glinka Prize. Dmitri Shostkovich worked closely with a quartet named for this composer, who wrote a tone poem that depicts a caravan of people represented by the English horn traveling through the desert with Russian soldiers. ","answer":"ANSWER: Alexander Borodin [accept the Borodin Quartet] (That tone poem is In the Steppes of Central Asia.) "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] Borodin was a member of a “mighty” school of this number of Russian composers. That school of this many Russian composers was also heavily influenced by Glinka’s music. This is also the number of lines that make up a musical staff. ","answer":"ANSWER: five [accept the Mighty Five] <Classical Music> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] Identify this unnamed character, who repeatedly tries to sell articles to a newspaper editor referred to as the “Commandor.” This character plans to write about a God-hating prostitute in his one-act play The Sign of the Cross. ","answer":"ANSWER: the protagonist of Hunger [accept any answer referring to the writer from Hunger or the narrator of Hunger; or answers referring to the hungry man from Hunger] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] As a Scandinavian novel from the 1890s about a young writer wandering around a city, Knut Hamsun’s Hunger could be grouped with this Swedish author’s Inferno. He also wrote the play Miss Julie. ","answer":"ANSWER: August Strindberg "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] Like the narrator of Hunger, this real-life author used medieval Norway as the setting for a work titled for the Cross. The Cross, The Wreath, and The Wife make up her trilogy about Kristin Lavransdatter. ","answer":"ANSWER: Sigrid Undset <European Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name these abstract entities that, along with a set of timepoints, are incorporated into first-order logic in Richard Montague’s (“MON-tuh-gyoo’s”) model of language. ","answer":"ANSWER: possible worlds "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] Montague was a pioneer in formal approaches to this subfield of linguistics, which studies denotation and meaning. ","answer":"ANSWER: natural language semantics "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] Montague’s most influential paper was titled for this process of binding free variables. One example of it is denoted with an upside-down capital “A,” and another is written with a backwards capital “E.” ","answer":"ANSWER: quantification [accept universal or existential quantifiers; accept “The Proper Treatment of Quantification in Ordinary English”; prompt on PTQ paper] <Social Science (Linguistics)> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"1. During the reign of these rulers, most real power was held by mayors of the palace. ","answer":"ANSWER: do-nothing kings [or rois fainéants] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] Because their long hair was a symbol of their royal lineage, the Merovingians forced claimants and deposed kings to undergo this procedure in which the scalp was shaved before being confined to a monastery. ","answer":"ANSWER: tonsure "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] The last ruler of this dynasty, Louis V, earned the nickname “Do-Nothing” because the nobility controlled his realm. Charlemagne belonged to this dynasty that assumed power under his grandfather Charles Martel. ","answer":"ANSWER: Carolingian Dynasty [or Karling Dynasty] <European History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] Identify this hyaluronan-rich plasma dialyzate. It is a rheopectic fluid rich in lubricin secreted by surface chondrocytes. ","answer":"ANSWER: synovial fluid [prompt on, but DO NOT REVEAL, answers referring to the fluid in joints] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] Synovial fluid is found within the cavity of these structures. DMARDs, such as the TNF-alpha inhibitor adalimumab, are used to treat a disease affecting these structures. ","answer":"ANSWER: synovial joints [or diarthrosis; accept plane, gliding, hinge, pivot, condyloid, ellipsoidal, saddle, ball and socket, or compound joints, but do not accept or prompt on any other type of joint] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] DMARDs are used to treat the rheumatoid form of this disease. In general, this term refers to diseases that affect joints, such as gout. ","answer":"ANSWER: arthritis [or rheumatoid arthritis; or gouty arthritis; prompt on RA] <Biology> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] In 2019, this boy band released “Sucker,” their first single together in six years, and reunited for their comeback album Happiness Begins. This band collaborated with Demi Lovato on her debut album Don’t Forget. ","answer":"ANSWER: The Jonas Brothers "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] In 1999, the Backstreet Boys released this lead single from their album Millennium. This song’s chorus repeatedly implores the listener to “tell me why” and states that “I never want to hear you say” the title phrase. ","answer":"ANSWER: “I Want It That Way” "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"0. Their debut album, which included a cover of “Didn’t I (Blow Your Mind This Time),” also received very little attention outside their native Boston. ","answer":"ANSWER: New Kids on the Block [prompt on NKOTB] <Pop Culture> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this director whose film Sebastiane (“seh-bas-tee-AH-nay”) is entirely in Latin and gave Tilda Swinton her screen debut. ","answer":"ANSWER: Derek Jarman "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] Jarman’s final feature film consists of a single shot of this color, which also names the first film in Krzysztof Kieślowski’s Three Colours trilogy. Abdellatif Kechiche directed a 2013 lesbian romance titled this “Is the Warmest Color.” ","answer":"ANSWER: blue [accept Blue Is the Warmest Color; accept Three Colors: Blue] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] Blue Movie is a notorious film by this director, whose Chelsea Girls influenced later queer filmmakers. He also directed controversial films like Empire and Blow Job. ","answer":"ANSWER: Andy Warhol [or Andrew Warhola] <Other Arts (Film)> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this author, who only received his Czech citizenship back in 2019 after previously being blacklisted there. He wrote the novel The Unbearable Lightness of Being. ","answer":"ANSWER: Milan Kundera "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] In The Art of the Novel, Kundera advocated structuring novels in this many parts, advice he has followed for all but one of his novels. The subtitle of his book The Curtain calls it “an essay in [this many] parts.” ","answer":"ANSWER: seven "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"M","question":"[10] This seven-part novel by Kundera is titled for two ways of dealing with life in occupied Prague. It begins with Mirek’s arrest while destroying old love letters, prefiguring Tamina’s later attempt to recover love letters. ","answer":"ANSWER: The Book of Laughter and Forgetting [or Kniha smíchu a zapomnění] <European Literature>"}]
